<!-- :xml.root=doc.xml: -->
<preface id="book_foreword">

<title>Foreword</title>
    <para>
        This is a the main documentation for the <application>JMathLib</application > Program.
    </para>
    <note>
        <title>Work in progress</title>
        <para>
            Like the <application>JMathLib</application > program this is a work in progress.
            All efforts will be made to keep the documentation in
            sync with the main program but it might not be completely
            up to date.
        </para>
    </note>


<para>
In mid of 2001 I was looking for a computational engine which has an easy 
scripting language and which should be very flexible. Also I did have no other 
projects to spend my leisure time on, the last project was finished and at work 
was no access to a flexible simulation tool like 
<ulink url="http://www.mathworks.com/">Matlab</ulink>. A search in the open 
source world on the internet came up with a couple of hits like octave, scilab,
rlab and some more. Some were already very advanced, but they are all written 
in C or C++ and I was looking for something in my favourite programming 
language, which is java. So finally I found 
<ulink url="http://mathlib.sourceforge.net">JMathLib</ulink>, which is hosted 
at sourceforge.net. The project had just started some months ago and only had 
one developer so far. This is when I met Mark Sparshatt and very soon I became 
an active member of the developing team. Which had the magical size of two 
individuals at that time.
</para>


<para>
Some of my other projects can be found 
<ulink url="http://www.held-mueller.de/">here</ulink>.
</para>
<para>

<mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="stefan_small.jpg" format="JPG" width="20%"/>
    </imageobject>
</mediaobject>


Hallo
<mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
	<imagedata fileref="drawingplain.svg" format="svg" />
    </imageobject>
</mediaobject>
you
</para>


<para>
Stefan M&uuml;ller  (2006/10/23)
</para>

</preface>
